So whenever you renew your vehicle's first party
insurance,
what things should you keep in mind?
Because when your vehicle is insured,
these small additions take up a lot of your
money. It is
very important to have this in your insurance advance.
Friends, this thing reduces the cost when your vehicle is completely lost, in a way, it has become a total
loss. So, I would
say that
making a video really takes a lot of hard work. Give a like and
subscribe. Hello Gas,
my name is Rahul. You are watching Poore
Jeev Blog. It has been a year since my car was insured, so
I had to renew its insurance as well. So
you all know that whenever you go to buy a new car, there is
a rule in India
that in the first insurance you will get both the insurances i.e.
first party and third
party and in your second and third insurance,
there will be only third party. So, you have to renew
your first party insurance every year.
You can see what additions you have to make in it.
What all things have I made in advance,
how much was the total amount of insurance.
We are making an information video so that you can  To make it
easier for people to insure their
vehicle, we have started our account on Instagram as well.
You
can come there and ask us questions, talk to us.
If you want to talk to me or
ask me something, you can come there and
ask me. The video is going to be very informative. If you liked the
video, please
like and subscribe to the channel. So first of all, let
me tell you from
where I got my vehicle insured.
I got my vehicle insured through
Maruti Suzuki itself. There is an online Maruti
site, you
can renew the insurance by going there. The insurance I have is from
SBI Journal Company Limited.
Now
what all things are included in it, what advance tax have
I paid? Look, first of all, the
price of your vehicle is there. There is
a cost for it
under the insurance, the cost of which was
4975, that is,
4975. And if I talk about it, it has been
one year since my vehicle was insured, so I had
not taken insurance, so I have
also got a no claim bonus, the value of which is
₹970, that is  I got the benefit of No Claim Bonus
of ₹970 and at the same time if we
see what all we have added in it
because this is the most important thing
when you buy your insurance,
renew your insurance, now what
advance did you take, see first of all
if we talk about advance then the
first advance is your Zero Dash, it is
very important to have it in your vehicle, I
mean friend, when you take your vehicle for insurance,
this child pays a lot of your money, now how much did it cost
me, when I turned off the Zero Deep,
if we look at it here,
I had to pay ₹4545 for the Zero Deep, that is
4543, along with this I have also taken Engine Garbage
Protection, what do you say, when you go on
such a road when you are doing a lot of
off-roading or going to a very hilly
area where there is a big
ravine, then what happens is that
some big stones go forward from below
towards the engine and damage the engine,
now if this thing is in your insurance
So you do
n't have to worry, but if this thing
is not included in your insurance, then it's going to
cost you a lot. It's going to cost
you a lot. When
we buy it,
how much does it cost for installation? How much does it cost us?
This is our 1363.
1363 means by adding 1300 rupees, you are protecting your engine in
a way. The third thing that is
very important is
your return invoice. It is
very important to have it in your insurance advance.
Friend, this thing reduces the cost there when your car is
completely lost. If we
talk about the price,
how much does it cost? So, I had to
pay 1514 rupees for this. 1514 rupees is spent on it for
replacement or key loss. If
your key is lost or you need to replace it, if there is
any problem, then you
pay 250 rupees in insurance for that. So, the cost of this key is a
huge
expense, brother.  Your entire
setup of 20-25000 rupees, which is installed inside the car, all those
things change but if
you add 250 rupees in your advance
then you can get back from this thing, 250 is
not a big deal for one year and what we
took in the last, your consumable parts, see
what are consumable parts, like if
your car goes in insurance, see, there are nuts,
balls, rubber, there are some such things
called and it happens to it
which consumes this car, now if you have
taken it then it will be included in the insurance, if you have
not taken it then
you will have to pay its money at the time of insurance,
how much will it cost me
when I took it in advance, 900 rupees,
99 rupees,
friend, see, I did not take many things in advance,
first I took the panel, second I took the
engine, third I took the return brother,
fourth I took the replacement steel of
fifth I took consumable parts, all these
things are important in your car insurance,
if we talk about the overall price
How much did I lose in this? My
price is for the first
part of the insurance, that is my
1473 SBI General Insurance which is
of Maruti Suzuki only. Now you all will
tell me that many companies can do the same thing, you could have
chosen that insurance also. Look, when you abuse the insurance of Maruti Suzuki, then
you can take a claim as many times in a year, I
mean I am not saying that your car has met with an
accident again and again, but if this happens then
you will not have any problem.
Maruti Suzuki has offered you unlimited claims
if you take the insurance of Maruti Suzuki.
If you
want a complete detailed video on how your car is being
covered by first and third party,
what is first party, what is third party, then
I have
made a detailed video on this, you will get the link in the description,
you can check it by going there.
Hopefully you must have liked the video. If you liked the video,
like the video,
comment and share it, I will apply it in your comment
and I will tell you one thing in small detail, it
really takes a lot of
hard work to make a video. By giving a like and subscribing